# Guanchu Wang

E-mail: hegsns@mail.ustc.edu.cn Phone number: +86 15256975943

### PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a post graduate student from department of Electronics & Communication Engineering (ECE) at University of Science and Technology of China (USTC). My researches involve reforce learning, signal process, radio charging, wireless communication and networks. Furthermore, I have broad interests in optimization and decision.

In 2016.9, I joined USTC ECE, where I was fortunate for having been directed by Prof. Chen Gong and Zhengyuan Xu, and my research topics include signal processing, multiple access communication and media access control. Before this, I finished my undergraduate study in Dalian University of Technology (DUT), where my researches focused on automatic driving of photoelectrical smart car.

From 2019.7 to 2019.9, I was working as an intern in Magcharging Inc. There I was fortunate to be directed by Prof. Xiaodong Wang from Columbia University and finished a prototype machine of radio frequency wireless charging system. Now, I am working as a research assistance in the Machine Intelligence Lab in Westlake university, and my current research focuses on deep reinforcement learning for robotics.

### **EDUCATION**

1. University of Science and Technology of China (USTC), Anhui, P.R.C.

M.S. in Information Science and Technology, 2016.9 - 2019.6.

Supervisor: Prof. Chen Gong.

Main courses: statistical learning, algorithms, matrix analysis, coding theory, etc.

**GPA:** 3.5/4.3 [Details]

**TOEFL:** 99/120 (Listening:25/30 Reading:26/30 Writing:27/30 Speaking:21/30). [Details]

GRE: 323 + 3.5 (Verbal:153 Quantitative:170 Writing:3.5). [Details]

Academics: [Google Scholar], [DBLP].

2. Dalian University of Technology (DUT), Liaoning, P.R.C.

B.S. in Information and Communication Engineering, 2012.9 - 2016.6.

Main courses: mathematical statistics, digital signal processing, information theory, communication theory, advanced mathematics, mathematical modeling, etc. [Details]

### WORKING EXPERIENCES

1. Magcharging Inc., Shenzhen, P.R.C., Researcher, 2019.7-2019.9. Industrial Mentor: Prof. Xiaodong Wang.

2. Westlake University, Hangzhou, P.R.C., Research assistance, 2019.9-Present. Advisor: Prof. Donglin Wang.

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCES

- 1. Machine Intellignece Lab in Westlake University, Hangzhou, P.R.C. Research assistance, 2019.10-now.
  - Deep reinforcement learning. [Details]
  - Multi-skill learning.
  - DIAYN, Soft-AC, DDPG.
- 2. Magcharging Inc., Shenzhen, P.R.C., Intern, 2019.7 2019.9.
  - Ratio frequency wirless charging: [Details]
  - MIMO, blind adaptive beamforming.
  - USRP implement (Labview), Backscattering communication.
- 3. Optical Wireless Communication and Network Center in USTC, Anhui, P.R.C. Postgraduate student, 2016.9 2019.6.
  - Optical network system: [Details]
  - IEEE 802.11 (transmission protocol, throughput analysis).
  - Multi-station access protocol (partner distribution, throughput analysis & optimization).
  - Multiple accessed system: [Details]
  - Hidden Markov Model.
  - Multi-user estimation, signal processing, correcting code.
  - Weak signal optical communication: [Details]
  - Digital signal processing algorithms (synchronization, estimation & symbol detection).
  - Error correcting code (convolutional, RS, LDPC code).
  - Hardware realization (Verilog-FPGA).
- 4. Laboratory of Smart Car in DUT, Liaoning, P.R.C., 2013-2014.
  - Automatic driving of photoelectrical smart car

### **PUBLICATIONS & PREPRINTS**

#### 1. Preprints:

- 1) **Guanchu Wang**, Chen Gong, Zhimeng Jiang, and Zhengyuan Xu, "A Double-station Access Protocol for Optical Wireless Scattering Communication Networks." [ArXiv]
- 2) Zhimeng Jiang, Chen Gong, **Guanchu Wang**, and Zhengyuan Xu, "On the Achievable Rate of a Sample-based Practical Photon-counting Receiver." [ArXiv]

### 2. Journal Publications:

- 1) Guanchu Wang, Chen Gong, Zhimeng Jiang, and Zhengyuan Xu, "Multi-layer Superimposed Transmission for Optical Wireless Scattering Communication." IEEE Photonics Journal, vol. 11, no. 5, Oct. 2019. [PDF]
- Guanchu Wang, Chen Gong, and Zhengyuan Xu, "Signal Characterization for Multiple Access Non-line of Sight Scattering Communication." IEEE Transaction on Communication, vol. 66, no. 9, pp. 4138-4154, Apr. 2018. [PDF]
- 3) Guanchu Wang, Kun Wang, Chen Gong, Difan Zou, Zhimeng Jiang, and Zhengyuan Xu, "A 1Mbps Real-time NLOS UV Scattering Communication System with Receiver Diversity over 1km." IEEE Photonics Journal, vol. 10, no. 2, Apr. 2018. [PDF]

#### 3. Conference Publications:

- 1) Zhimeng Jiang, Chen Gong, **Guanchu Wang**, and Zhengyuan Xu, "Achievable Rate Bounds on Poisson Channel with a Sample-based Practical Photon-counting Receiver." IEEE International Conference on Communications(ICC), Shanghai, China, May 20-24, 2019. [PDF]
- Guanchu Wang, Chen Gong, Zhimeng Jiang, Zhengyuan Xu, "Characterization on Asynchronous Multiple Access in Non-line of Sight Scattering Communication." IEEE International Conference on Communications (ICC), Kansas City, MO, USA, May 20-24, 2018. [PDF]
- 3) Guanchu Wang, Chen Gong, and Zhengyuan Xu, "Signal detection and achievable rates for multiple access optical wireless scattering communication." IEEE Global Communications Conference(Globecom), Singapore, Dec. 4-8, 2017. [PDF]

### **HONORS & AWARDS**

- 1. Major Awards, USTC, 2016, 2017, 2018.
- 2. Outstanding Graduate, Dalian, 2016.
- 3. Outstanding Bachelor Thesis, DUT, 2016.
- 4. National Second Prize, China National Mathematical Modeling Contest, 2016.
- 5. Honorable Mention, Mathematical Contest in Modeling (MCM), 2016.
- 6. Scholarship of Academic and Innovation, DUT, 2013, 2014, 2015.
- 7. Scholarship of Sumitomo Corporation, DUT, 2013.

#### ACADEMIC SERVICES

- 1. Journal/Conference Reviewer: IEEE Trans. Commun., IEEE Trans. Ind. Electron., IEEE/OSA J. Lightwave Technol., IEEE Commun. Lett.; ICC Workshop.
- 2. Visiting student, Institute of electronics, Chinese Academy of science, Beijing China, Aug. 2015.
- 3. Participant, International conference on Optical Wireless Communication, Beijing China, July 2017.
- 4. Poster, IEEE Global Communication Conference, Singapore, Dec 2017.
- 5. Presentation, IEEE International Conference on Communications, Kansas USA, May 2018.
- 6. Participant, Shanghai Tech Workshop on Information, Learning and Decision, June 2018.

## KEY SKILLS

- 1. Python, Matlab, Verilog, C++/C.
- 2. Route planning, numerical optimization, system simulation, and statistics.
- 3. Labview/USRP, Verilog/ISE/FPGA.
- 4. Cooperation and teamwork.